Finding Aid for the Paul D. Boyer Papers, 1943-2009 LSC.2156
UCLA Library Special Collections
Paul D. Boyer papers
1943-2009
1960-1993
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.2156
19.4 Linear Feet (47 boxes and 3 half boxes)
Paul D. Boyer won the Nobel Prize in Chemistry in 1997 for his research on the binding change mechanism and rotational catalysis of the ATP synthase complex, which he performed at UCLA in the 1960-70s. This collection contains his professional papers, documenting his career as an academic at the University of Minnesota (1946-1963) and UCLA (1963-present [Emeritus]), where he was Director of the Molecular Biology Institute (MBI). Of particular note is Boyer's correspondence with other major bioenergeticists of the twentieth century including Efraim Racker and Nobelist Peter Mitchell, and regarding UCLA specifically, the naming of UCLA's Boyer Hall on campus.
Conditions on Access
Open for research, with the following exceptions: restricted student and award nominee information. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
CONTAINS UNPROCESSED DIGITAL MATERIALS: Digital materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Paul D. Boyer, 2014.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9980221293606533
Biography/History
Paul D. Boyer (1918–present) was born on July 31st, 1918 in Provo, Utah. He graduated from Brigham Young University with a B.S. in chemistry in 1939, was awarded a Wisconsin Alumni Research Foundation Scholarship, and began his doctoral work at the University of Wisconsin in 1939 in the lab of Paul H. Philips. Five days before leaving Provo, Boyer married fellow BYU student Lyda Whicker. He received his PhD in biochemistry from the University of Wisconsin in 1943, and moved to Stanford to work in the lab of J. Murray Luck on a war-related research project on the stabilization of serum albumin for transfusions. In 1945 Boyer was drafted into the U.S. Navy (second class seaman) and sent to the Navy Medical Research Institute. In 1946 he became an Assistant Professor at University of Minnesota. In 1955 Boyer received a Guggenheim Fellowship to work with Nobelist Hugo Theorell on alcohol dehydrogenase in Sweden, and also won the Award in Enzyme Chemistry from the American Chemical Society (ACS) that year. In 1956 Boyer accepted the Hill Foundation Professorship at the University of Minnesota and moved to the medical campus. He served as Chairman of the Biochemistry Section of the American Chemical Society from 1959-60.
In 1963 Boyer moved to UCLA, and in 1965 accepted the more administrative Directorship of the new Molecular Biology Institute (MBI). From 1969-70 Boyer also served as President of the American Society of Biological Chemists. In late 1970 Boyer's lab made a breakthrough discovery, formulating the first major aspect of what, along with his later theory of catalytic cooperativity (developed in the mid-1970s), became the binding change mechanism. He was eventually awarded the 1997 Nobel Prize in Chemistry for this research, after John Walker's crystallographic studies confirmed Boyer's formulation (Boyer, Walker, and Jens Skou shared the 1997 Prize).
From 1963-89 Boyer served as either Editor or Associate Editor of the Annual Review of Biochemistry, and from 1970-90 he was the Editor of the multivolume biochemistry series The Enzymes. In addition to his Nobel Prize he received numerous awards, including the Rose Award of the American Society of Chemistry and Molecular Biology (1989) and honorary doctorates from the Universities of Stockholm (1974), Minnesota (1996), and Wisconsin (1998). He is a Member of the National Academy of Sciences. Boyer's lab largely stopped preforming research around 1993, and after which he spent an increasing amount of his time in Wyoming with his wife, Lyda. They have three children (Gail, Hali, and Douglas) and eight grandchildren.
Scope and Content
This collection contains materials largely related to Paul Boyer's professional career, most significantly research notes, article manuscripts, conference attendance, and correspondence related to his Nobel Prize-winning research on the binding change mechanism and rotational catalysis in the ATP synthase complex. This collection is especially strong in correspondence, containing Boyer's extensive research correspondence with Nobelist Peter Mitchell, bioenergeticist Efraim Racker, Richard Cross, Britton Chance, Henry Lardy, and James Peter. The collection also contains extensive article manuscripts with data, notes, and revisions. Lastly, the collection contains UCLA-specific materials such as documentation of the beginnings of the MBI, the naming of Boyer Hall, and the creation of the Boyer Postdoctoral fund.
Arrangement
Overall, materials are arranged alphabetically by topic within their series, then chronologically.
This collection has been arranged into the following series:
Series 1: Academia, 1941-2008
Subseries 1.1: Teaching, Academic Appointments, Personal Information, 1941-1999
Subseries 1.2: Publications, 1949-2007
Subseries 1.3: Conferences, 1967-2005
Subseries 1.4: Professional Societies, 1955-2008
Subseries 1.5: UCLA, 1974-2009
Series 2: Correspondence, 1943-2009
Series 3: Awards and Donations, 1951-2009
Series 4: Government Funding and Contracts, 1955-1995
Related Material
Donald J. Cram papers, 1937-2002, UCLA Library Special Collections (Collection 570).
Glenn Theodore Seaborg diaries, 1927-1946, UCLA Library Special Collections (Collection 1498).
University of California, Los Angeles. Department of Chemistry and Biochemistry--Faculty -- Archives
- Series 1: Academia, 1941-2008; 1960-1993
  Scope and Content
  This series (1941-2008) includes material related to Boyer's occupation as a professor, including article and book chapter manuscripts; conference lectures, notes, and programs; UCLA graduate seminar lecture notes; research notes and data; employment paperwork from University of Minnesota and UCLA; professional societies and editorial materials; and photographs of him and his colleagues. This series also contains correspondence and co-authored drafts/notes relating to specific articles or chapters. In terms of UCLA material, the series documents Boyer's Directorship of the Molecular Biology Institute (MBI) at UCLA, the UC Program for Research and Training in Biotechnology (also called the Systemwide Biotechnology Research and Education Program), his involvement with other UCLA campus institutes, the proceedings of UCLA advisory committees he served on, and information regarding the proposed Veloway bicycle highway project near UCLA's campus in Westwood. For material related to the naming of Boyer Hall, the creation of the Paul Boyer Endowed Chair at UCLA, and the Boyer Postdoctoral Fellowships at UCLA, see series 3.
  Arrangement
  Materials are sorted by document type (academic appointment, article, conference, etc.) within the subseries.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  COLLECTION CONTAINS DIGITAL MATERIALS: Special equipment or further processing may be required for viewing. To access digital materials you must notify the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk in advance of your visit.
  Restrictions on Access
  CONTAINS RESTRICTED MATERIAL: Contains restricted student information.
  - Subseries 1.1: Teaching, Academic Appointments, Personal Information, 1941-1999; 1960-1995
    This subseries contains materials documenting Boyer's academic appointments and offers from other institutions, his course materials for the undergraduate and graduate classes that he taught while at UCLA, as well as some of his personal research notes.
    - Academic Appointments: CVs and BYU transcript., 1944-1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Academic Appointments: Hill Professorship, University of Minnesota., 1954-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Academic Appointments: Hill Family Foundation, Fiscal Year Reports., 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Academic Appointments: Hill Family Foundation Fiscal Year Reports., 1961-1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Academic Appointments: Hill Professorship, Annual Outline of Activities/Reports., 1954-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Academic Appointments: Notice of Appointment (Employment paperwork), University of Minnesota., 1946-1962 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Academic Appointments: Stanford postdoc and University of Minnesota professorship., 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Academic Appointments: offers to leave University of Minnesota (incl. UCLA) (1 of 2)., 1946-1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Academic Appointments: offers to leave University of Minnesota (incl. UCLA) (2 of 2)., 1946-1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Academic Appointments: UCLA job offer., 1961-1963 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Academic Appointments: UCLA, possible transfer to UCLA Medical School faculty., 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Classes: Chemistry 22 course reader, Winter 1976. (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Classes: Biochemistry 152 miscellaneous exams over the years., 1977-1982 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Classes: Chemistry 22 Final, Winter 1977. (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Classes: Chemistry 251D, Winter 1977. (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Classes: Chemistry 256C, Spring 1977. (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Classes: Chemistry 256C, course evals, Spring 1977. (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Classes: Chemistry 268, Fall 1977. (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Classes: Chemistry 262, Winter 1978. (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Classes: Chemistry M-298, Spring 1978. (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Classes: Chemistry 152, Fall 1978. (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Classes: Chemistry 152 current lectures, Fall 1978. (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Classes: Chemistry 152 grading, Fall 1978. (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Classes: Chemistry 152 rough lecture notes, 1980. (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Classes: Chemistry 262, Winter 1980. (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Classes: Chemistry 262, course evals, Winter 1980. (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Classes: Chemistry 268, Winter 1980. (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Classes: Chemistry 152 class grades, Fall 1980. (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Classes: Chemistry 152 Exam Midterm makeup, Fall 1980. (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Classes: Chemistry 152 Midterm exam, 1980. (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Classes: Biochemistry 268 Student Seminars, Winter 1981. (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - Classes: Biochemistry 258 student seminars, Fall 1981. (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Classes: Biochemistry 262, Winter 1982. (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Classes: Biochemistry 268 student seminar, Winter 1982. (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Classes: Chemistry 152 course reader, Fall 1982. (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Classes: Chemistry 152 exam record, Fall 1982. (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Classes: Biochemistry, Molecular Biology seminars Spring 1983. (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Classes: Biochemistry 258, student seminar, Spring 1983. (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Classes: Biochemistry 258 student seminar, Winter 1984. (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Classes: Biochemistry 262, Winter 1984. (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Classes: Biochemistry 258 student seminar, Winter 1985. (Box 50, Folder 16)
    - Classes: Chemistry 157B, Spring 1985. (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Classes: Chemistry 157B class materials, Spring 1985. (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Classes: Chemistry 157B class notes, Spring 1985. (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Classes: Chemistry 157B notes, Spring 1985. (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Classes: Biochemistry 268 - seminar Fall 1985. (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Classes: Biochemistry 262 (Biological Energy Transductions) lectures, discussions Winter 1986. (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Classes: Biochemistry 262 (Biological Energy Transductions) miscellaneous materials, Winter 1986. (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - Classes: Chemistry 262 student handouts, Winter 1986. (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Classes: UCLA Commencement Program, 1999. (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Education: Boyer, Masters and PhD Theses, University of Wisconsin., 1941-1943 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Lab Members: List of Boyer's research associates, postdocs, grad students at U of Minnesota and UCLA., 1946-1987 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Personal: Curriculum Vitae and Biographical Sketches (1 of 2)., 1979-1997 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Personal: Curriculum Vitae and Biographical Sketches (2 of 2)., 1979-1997 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Personal: List of academic publications., undated (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Personal: regarding Lars Ernster (orbituary, misc. articles)., 1975, 1996-1999 (Box 20, Folder 7)
      Contains materials related to Lars Ernster such as copies of his articles and notifications of his passing. Also included is a memoir that Boyer wrote about their friendship for The Chemical Intelligencer upon invitation by the magazine's editor Istvan Hargittai.
    - Personal: regarding John Walker., 1996, 2003 (Box 20, Folder 8)
      Contains misc. correspondence, curriculum vitae, and a list of publications by John Walker, as well as an interview between him and the Academic Press.
    - Photographs., circa 1950-1998 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Research Notes: "Current Ideas and Problems" Brainstorming (1 of 2)., 1945-1985 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Research Notes: "Current Ideas and Problems" Brainstorming (2 of 2)., 1945-1985 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Research Notes: "Ox. Phos. General, Misc., and Current"., 1953-1954 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Research Notes: Exchange Kinetics Equations, Derivations, Notes, and Correspondence., 1958-1974 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Research Notes: 18 O Methodology and Related Reaction Rates., 1973-2000 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Research Notes: P i to HOH Exchange Rate, Wolcott 1977. (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Research Notes: "Ratchet Mechanism, One Way, and Related" Material., 1979 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Research Notes: "Reaction Rates and 18 O Exchanges"., before 1982 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Research Notes: "18 O Medium Exchange Calculations (for Raj's DMSO data)"., 1985 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Research Notes: "Sequence-Misc. Synthase Data"., 1985-1991 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Research Notes: Ox Phos Reaction Rates with Kathryn LaNoue., 1987-1990 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Research Notes: Kinetics material (misc.)., 1987-1991 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Sabbaticals: NIH Sabbatical, Spring Quarter 1979. (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Sabbaticals: Oxford, Spring 1984., 1982 (Box 24, Folder 11)
  - Subseries 1.2: Publications, 1949-2007; 1970-2002
    Contains Boyer's numerous authored/co-authored articles and book chapters. Frequent co-authors include Michael Gresser, Vladimir Kasho, Yakov M. Milgrom, Marat Murataliev, and Teri Melese. Subseries also contains a number of publications by Peter Mitchell and miscellaneously authored titles, as well as folders including loose prints, transparencies, and negatives of Boyer's article figures, tables, and charts.
    Materials are arranged by first author as it appears on the published version, then chronologically.
    - Articles: Amory, Goffeau, McIntosh, and Boyer, "Exchange of oxygen between phosphate and water catalyzed by the plasma membrane ATPase..."., 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Articles: Ariki and Boyer, "ATP and Ca 2+ Modulation of Catalytic Pathways for Pi Release by Sarcoplasmic Reticulum ATPase"., 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Articles: Ariki and Boyer, "18 O-Probes of phosphoenzyme formation and cooperativity with sarcoplasmic reticulum ATPase"., 1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Articles: Ariki and Boyer, "Characterization of Medium P i to HOH Exchanges Catalyzed by Sarcoplasmic Reticulum Vesicles "., 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Articles: Baykov, Kasho, Bakuleva, and Rea, "Characterization of Oxygen Exchange Reactions Catalyzed by...H +-PPase"., 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Articles: Berkich, Williams, Masiakos, Smith, Boyer, and La Noue, "Rates of Various Reactions Catalyzed by ATP synthase..." (1 of 2)., 1985-1991 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Articles: Berkich, Williams, Masiakos, Smith, Boyer, and La Noue, "Rates of Various Reactions Catalyzed by ATP synthase..." (2 of 2)., 1985-1991 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Articles: Bild and Boyer, "Subunit Interaction during Catalysis: Ammonium Ion Modulation of Catalytic Steps in the E. coli Glutamine Synthetase Reaction"., 1978-1980 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Articles: Bild, Janson, and Boyer, "Subunit Interaction during Catalysis: ATP Modulation of Catalytic Steps in the Succinyl CoA Synthetase Reaction"., 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Articles: Boyer, "The Investigator, the University and Research"., 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Articles: Boyer, "Uses and Limitations of Measurements of Rates of Isotopic Exchange and Incorporation in Catalyzed Reactions"., 1958-1960, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 11)
      Includes a 2007 note from Professor Boyer regarding the importance of his team's development of (initially rejected) exchange rates equations for the enzyme kinetics community.
    - Articles: Boyer, "Labelling Rates and Detection of Intermediates in Mitochondrial Phosphorylation..."., 1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Articles: Boyer, "Oxidative and Photosynthetic Phosphorylation..."., 1967 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Articles: Boyer, Cross, and Momsen, "A New Concept for Energy Coupling in Oxidative Phosphorylation"., 1973 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Articles: Boyer, "Conformation Coupling in Oxidative Phosphorylation and Photophosphorylation"., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Articles: Boyer, "Isotope Exchange Probes and Enzyme Mechanisms"., 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Articles: Boyer, "Spectrophotometric Study of the Reaction of Protein Sulfhydryl Groups with Organic Mercurials"., 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Articles: Boyer, "Bioenergetic coupling to proton motive force..."., 1983-2007 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Articles: Boyer, "The Case for a Return to Fixed Indirect Costs"., 1986 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Articles: Boyer, "The binding change mechanism for ATP synthase". +1 Floppy disc., 1991-1992 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Contains 1 floppy disc titled "Boyer-Disc 9 Review-2 6/22/92"
    - Articles: Boyer, "From Human Serum Albumin to Rotational Catalysis"., 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Articles: Boyer, "Annual Review article on ATP"., 1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Articles: Boyer, "The ATP synthase - A Splendid Molecular Machine" (1 of 2)., 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Articles: Boyer, "The ATP synthase - A Splendid Molecular Machine" (2 of 2)., 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Articles: Boyer, "ATP synthase - Past and Future"., 1998 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Articles: Boyer, "Catalytic site forms and controls in ATP synthase catalysis"., 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Articles: Boyer, "What Makes ATP Synthase Spin?". +1 Floppy disc., 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Contains 1 floppy disc titled "Adobe Illus. 6.0 (Mac)"
    - Articles: Boyer, "Catalytic site occupancy during ATP synthase catalysis"., 2001 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Articles: Boyer, "New Insights into One of Nature's Remarkable Catalysts, the ATP synthase"., 2001 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Articles: Boyer, "Toward an Adequate Scheme for the ATP synthase Catalysis ". +3 Floppy Discs., 2001 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      Contains 3 floppy discs. First one titled "adv. As corrected 6/3/01 | file: corrections | Russia | 5/28/01 with figures in text. As correted 6/3/01". Second one titled "adv-r 6/9/01 | russia 6/11/01 11/2 space". Third one titled "BIOKHIMIYA | File adv - as corrected 6/3/01 | 'russia' ' ' 'corrections"
    - Articles: Boyer, "A Research Journey with ATP synthase", reflection article for JBC., 2001-2002 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Articles: Boyer, "Catalytic site occupancy during ATP synthase catalysis"., 2002 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Articles: Boyer and Wu, "Bound ATP formation, Bound ADP and Pi Retention..."., 1984-1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Articles: Boyer and misc. authors, "Oxidative Phosphorylation and Photophosphorylation" review (1 of 4)., 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Articles: Boyer and misc. authors, "Oxidative Phosphorylation and Photophosphorylation" review (2 of 4)., 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Articles: Boyer and misc. authors, "Oxidative Phosphorylation and Photophosphorylation" review (3 of 4)., 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Articles: Boyer and misc. authors, "Oxidative Phosphorylation and Photophosphorylation" review (4 of 4)., 1974-1977 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Articles: Cardon and Boyer, "The Rate of Release of ATP from its Complex with Myosin"., 1978 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Articles: Cardon and Boyer, "Subunit Interaction in Catalysis: Some Experimental & Theoretical Approaches with G3P Dehydrogenase"., 1979-1982 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Articles: Champeil, Guillain, Venien, Gingold "Interaction of Mg and Pi with calcium deprived SR ATPase"., 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Articles: Choate, Hutton, and Boyer, "Occurence and Significance of Oxygen Exchange..."., 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Articles: de Meis and Boyer, "Induction by Nucleotide Triphosphate hydrolysis of a Form of Sarcoplasmic Reticulum ATPase..."., 1977 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Articles: Du and Boyer, "Control of ATP Hydrolysis...as Related to Protonmotive Force"., 1988 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Articles: Du and Boyer, "Sulfite activation of the chloroplast thylakoid ATPase..."., 1989 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Articles: Ernster, Carlsson, and Boyer, "Reconstituted Mitochondrial Oligomycin-sensitive ATPase..."., circa 1977 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Articles: Feldman and Boyer, "The Role of Tightly Bound ADP on Chloroplast ATPase"., 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Articles: Gafni and Boyer, "Characterization of Sarcoplasmic Reticulum ATP..."., 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Articles: Gafni and Boyer, "Modulation of Stoichiometry of the Sarcoplasmic Reticulum..."., 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Articles: Gresser, Myers, and Boyer, "ATPase Correlations" (1 of 2)., 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Articles: Gresser, Myers, and Boyer, "ATPase Correlations" (2 of 2)., 1980-1982 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Articles: Gresser, Rosen, and Boyer, "Demonstration and Quantification of Catalytic and Non-catalytic Bound ATP..."., 1979 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Articles: Gresser, "Presence of Considerable Bound Catalytic ADP during ATP Hydrolysis by F1 ATPase"., 1980 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Articles: Gresser and Boyer, "Negative Cooperativity is Observed for ATP Hydrolysis by Beef Heart Mitochondrial F1 ATPase"., 1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Articles: Guerrero, Xue, and Boyer, "Active/Inactive state transitions of chloroplast F1 ATPase..."., 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Articles: Guerrero, Ehler, and Boyer, "GTP and FTP bind at noncatalytic nucleotide..."., 1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Articles: Guillain and Boyer, "Correlation of Intrinsic Fluorescence and Oxygen-exchange Measurements of Phosphorylation of Sarcoplasmic Reticulum ATPase from Inorganic Phosphate"., 1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Articles: Guillain, Champeil, and Boyer, "Sarcoplasmic Reticulum ATPase..."., 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Articles: Hackney and Boyer, "Subunit Interaction During Catalysis"., 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Articles: Hackney and Boyer, "Evaluation of the Partitioning of Bound Inorganic Phosphate during medium and intermediate..."., 1978 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Articles: Hackney, Rosen, and Boyer, "Subunit interaction during catalysis..." (31 P NMR-chloroplasts)., 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Articles: Hackney, "Variation in the Partitioning of Bound Phosphate During Medium and Intermediate..."., 1979 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Articles: Hart, Stempel, Boyer, and Cormier, "Mechanism of Enzyme-catalyzed Bioluminescent Oxidation"., 1978 (Box 6, Folder 12)